hi bre and tras here going to show you a
video about the foot and shoulder
elevated hip thrust which I really like
uh and and it's funny I it took me a
while to really wrap my brain around
this I was talking to my friend Nick to
manella about a year ago some of the
things he he was saying it didn't click
at the time and now it does now that I
know more about biomechanics but I'm
amazed that I didn't think about this
but uh basically I'm going to I'm going
I have three choices I can put my heels
on on the box I can put the middle of my
feet or I can kind of go more through my
toes so those are the three options and
I actually like all three of them and I
do all three of them from time to time I
kind of switch them around and I I like
all three for different purposes for
example on on your toes you know when
you sprint you come down on on your
toes but I think that heels might have
more hamstring uh you know more
posterior chain but again you can
experiment with all three of those but
basically this is what I never thought
of when I just get my butt off the
ground this is a a knee flexion
exercise right now my hamstrings are
turned on big time I am doing this is
this is kind of like a leg curl
component right this is almost like a
seated leg curl motion here so I have a
kn KNE flexion component while I extend
the hips so again knee flexion and then
I come up and then about here there's
not much knee flexion but there's hip
extension
so the lower I go you know the more
Dynamic that knee flexion and extension
becomes but I'm using the hamstrings as
both knee flexors and hip extensors
which is what I like about this movement
and then when you do it one leg at a
time now you're introducing rotary
forces throughout the spine and pelvis
um and so it makes it a really really
challenging exercise um the other thing
I like is that this range up here right
in here this is my hips a hips neutral
position and that's the range of motion
more associated with ground contact when
you sprint you need to be very strong
and powerful in that range of motion and
so uh again I'll go over proper form all
right heels midfoot or whole foot on the
on the box okay get your butt off the
ground head and neutral head and neck
and
neutral squeeze right here squeeze the
glutes forward don't let your spine Anor
or your pelvis Anor pelvic tilt or your
lumbar spine hyperextend use the glutes
to
control the lumbar spine and pelvis so
you're using the glutes as uh hip
extension but also as anti- anter pelvic
tilters and anti- Lumbar expensers okay
so two legs at a
time just like this now right here
glutes glutes glutes then one
leg raise this butt on the
ground squeeze lower it slowly you
always want the Ecentric you know to pay
attention to the Ecentric contraction
too because a lot of people just plop
down make sure you come up to a full
range control your amount of uh lumbar
extension and anterior pelvic tilt by
using the glutes and uh don't sway from
side to side if you if you can't control
yourself laterally or Ro rotary forces
then you don't belong doing the single
leg stick to the double leg until you're
coordinated enough and then move to the
single leg